# Mustafa Dagteki

Spring Hill, TN 37174, USA | (615)877-2387 | mustafa.dagteki@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/mdagteki

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

With a decade of international experience in Data and Business Analytics, I specialize in providing practical insights and crafting efficient analytics solutions to support business goals. My keen attention to detail and collaborative problem-solving set me apart. Excited to bring my skills to a role that values in-depth analysis and creative use of data technologies, I'm eager to join your team and embrace this new chapter in my professional journey.

#### **SKILLS**

Data Analysis & Interpretation | Statistical Analysis | Reporting & Dashboard Creation | Data Cleaning & Processing | Requirements Gathering | Stakeholder Relations | Effective Communication | Problem-Solving | Financial Analysis | Project Management | Collaboration & Teamwork | Time Management | Business Intelligence | Analytical Thinking

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Excel (Advanced Functions) | SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) | Power BI | Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, SciPy, Stats Models) | Microsoft Power Query | Pivot Tables | T-SQL | SSRS | SSIS | SSAS | Azure Synapse Studio

#### **PROFESSIONAL HISTORY**

- ☐ Department Manager, Kroger Co, Franklin, TN | Jan 2019 Current
  - Ensured compliance with regulations, fostering a culture of trust and respect, and optimized departmental performance through effective scheduling strategies.
  - Meticulously managed inventory/stock conditions, addressing discrepancies, and increased sales and decreased shrink ratio by implementing proper ordering and pricing techniques. Also developed and implemented effective strategies to increase sales and profitability in the department.
  - Collaborate with upper management and cross-functional teams to develop and implement strategies to improve departmental performance and customer satisfaction and meet sales goals.
- ☐ Data Analyst and BI Consultant, Greenalyzed, Mersin, Turkey | Mar 2013 Dec 2018
  - Executed 21 detailed project analyses focusing on feasibility, productivity, and profitability, contributing to a 20% increase in productivity and a 15% rise in profitability.
  - Skillfully collected and cleansed data across 80+ diverse datasets utilizing SQL, Python, Power Query, and Excel, ensuring high-quality data for accurate analysis.
  - Developed 40+ data products, including dynamic dashboards, comprehensive reports, and key performance indicators (KPIs), using SQL, Python, Power BI, and Excel, to facilitate data-driven decision-making.

• Assisted and advised following companies on enhancing Data Analytics and Business Intelligence capabilities : AgriLion Tarim, Ocak Ferforje, Vatan Sera, VTS Proje, SUNBATU, Hapek Yapi, Metas Seracilik.

# ☐ Data Analyst and BI Coordinator, Aytekin Group, Mersin, Turkey | Jan 2007 - Mar 2013

- Engineered and deployed comprehensive data and reporting infrastructures from scratch for 5 distinct companies using Excel, SQL, and ERP solutions, enabling real-time insights, enhancing the data-driven decision-making process and integrating complex production modules into ERP systems, boosting productivity tracking and efficiency by 20%.
- Analyzed, produced, and delivered over 350 ad-hoc, monthly, quarterly, and annual financial and productivity reports, enhancing stakeholder comprehension and engagement with complex data by 40%. and innovated budgeting tools incorporating predictive modeling to establish more accurate financial targets for various companies; also developed complex pivot tables and advanced visualizations for comparative analysis using SQL, Power BI, and Excel.
- Led and collaborated within cross-functional teams of 10+ members, driving a more precise and effective data analytics approach across multiple projects and conducting in-depth analyses of project productivity and company performance, identifying key areas for improvement.

# ☐ Data Analyst, Nazzal Industry Ltd, Mersin, Turkey | Oct 2005 - Jan 2007

- Developed and deployed an SQL-based ERP system, enhancing operational efficiency.
- Conducted data analyses using Excel, identifying key business insights.
- Crafted dynamic PowerPoint reports to improve stakeholder understanding.

### ☐ Contract Operations Manager, Serka Contracting, Mosul, Iraq | Jan 2004 - Oct 2005

- Managed budgets across multiple contracts using Excel, ensuring financial compliance and adherence to regulations, and supervised payroll and budgeting for a team of 150 personnel, utilizing Excel to optimize operational expenses.
- Implemented cost-effective logistics solutions for a fleet of 60 vehicles, controlling expenses and maintaining operational efficiency with Excel spreadsheets, and mitigated operational risks and ensured service continuity in challenging conditions, supported by Excel for data analysis and planning.
- Fostered a collaborative work environment among a culturally diverse team, using Excel for communication and data management, and utilized Excel for financial analysis to allocate resources effectively and maximize operational efficiency.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor's Degree in Economics, The University of Cukurova
- Associate Degree in Business Management, Eastern Gateway Community College
- Trade and Accounting High school

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Professional Data Analyst Certification (SQL & Python) | SQL Associate Certification | Data Engineer Associate Certification | Python Programming Certification |